Mohammad Amin Asadi

Deep Learning - Computer Vision Engineer

Mashhad, Iran mohammad-amin-asadi_github.io mohammadasadiamin@gmail.com

github.com/mohammad-amin-asadi linkedin.com/in/mohammad-amin-asadi/



Experienced computer vision engineer with multiple national awards in computer vision: self-driving cars competitions, specializing in Python, TensorFlow, and OpenCV, Over 5 years of programming experience, focusing on AI and deep learning, including notable achievements in autonomous vehicle competitions.

Skills

Current Stack:

- Python
- Tensorflow
- Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN)
- Deep Learning
- Machine Learning
- Linux
- Yolo models
- MediaPipe
- Image Classification
- SQL
- Docker
- RabbitMQ
- HuggingFace

Transformers

- ONNX
- TensorRT
- Object detection
- Object Segmentation
- Large Vision Models

Prior Stack:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Jquery
- Django
- DRF

Experiences

<u>Rapid Solutions International, UAE (Remote)</u> - Tech-lead Warehouse Automation Projects In Computer Vision Projects...... Sep2024 - Present

- Develop and Optimize Vision Models. Enhance CNN Model Performance with ONNX.
- Implement Image Enhancement Techniques using OpenCV. Optimize Model Serving with RabbitMQ.
- Research and Manage Large Image Datasets. Create and Maintain Technical Documentation.
- Collaborate with Cross-functional Teams for Model Deployment. Study and Apply Latest Computer Vision Research.
- Oversee Team Collaboration and Mentorship. Improve Model Accuracy and Training Processes.
- Drive Innovation in Warehouse Automation Solutions.

<u>Department of Artificial Intelligence Research Center PartAI, Mashhad Iran</u>— Computer Vision

Researcher and Developer...... Oct 2023 - Oct 2024

- Researched and developed more than 10 vision and large vision models.
- Excellent experience in team collaboration within a computer vision team of over 12 members.
- Optimized CNN models using ONNX and model tuning up to 10x when serving models on CPUs.
- Enhanced images with preprocessing OpenCV algorithms (smoothing, sharping, and ...).
- Boosted computer vision models serving with a powerful RabbitMQ message-broker.
- Researched large image datasets for faster and more efficient model training.
- Documented more than 30 Wikis for explaining the R&D of every service to DevOps and other teammates.
- Exploring and Studying computer vision papers to improve our training processes.

Freelancer — Computer Vision Engineer...... Jan 2023 - Oct 2023

- Designing a real-time GUI Cross-platform Persian plate recognition desktop application for an automatic parking management system using YOLOv8, YOLO-NAS, and Tkinter for Detection and GUI desktop design with +95% accuracy on +1000 real-world testing images.
- Creating one of the biggest Persian plate datasets in Roboflow with ~5000 annotated unique images, more than 100 times downloaded and 1142 times viewed.
- Training and evaluating cutting-edge Object Detection models (Yolo, Efficient Det, and ...).
- Inventing an AI application that could help blind people walk in streets more easily and safely using Raspberry PI 4, detection model, and ultrasonic SRF sensors.

I3center, **Mashad**, **Iran** — Python tutor...... Jan 2022 - Nov 2022

- Teaching passionate Python learners and programming lovers.
- Creating online and video Python studying content during the coronavirus pandemic.
- Active online support for both online and face-to-face classrooms.
- Tutoring Python from basics to Object Oriented Programming (OOP) level.

Amirkabir Vocational School Academy of Brilliant Talents, Mashhad, Iran — Computer Vision Engineer and Robotics Vision tutor (I was also a student in this Academy)...... SEP 2020- JUNE 2023

- Cultivating vision, science and knowledge in the minds of talented teenagers.
- Building an auto-student-attendance application with Face Recognition technology and RSTP protocol cameras.
- Constructed and led an association of Robotics and AI at Amirkabir Academy.
- Trained and coached Al-talented students with autonomous simulators like Gazebo and AVIS-Engine.

<u>Toopita</u> & <u>Telefonchy</u>, mashhad, Iran — Junior Front-end Developer & Technical

Support..... OCT 2019 - DEC 2020

- Starting my IT career in a high-tech VOIP service company as a front-end developer.
- Learning and developing front-end websites using HTML, CSS, Jquery, JS, and a sip of PHP.
- After a few months, I started writing Python web-scraping applications so that the application could find company phone numbers and contact information from their websites.
- Solving +300 customers' problems in their VOIP experiences.
- Updating and managing companies' VOIP lines as needed.

Awards

All awards and certificates are available here -> Google Drive Link

- Tirst Place in the self-driving cars (Pro League) competition of the ICROM AmirKabir University, (Simulator) 2024 (Coach)
- Y First Place in the exhilarating self-driving cars (Pro League) competition of the IRAN Tech Olympics, (Simulator race) 2024. (Member)
- First Place in the exhilarating self-driving cars U19 competition of the <u>IRAN Tech Olympics</u>, showcasing my prowess in technical Coaching and leadership (Simulator) 2024. (Team Coach)
- First Place in the exhilarating self-driving cars U19 competition of the IRAN Fira Cup's League, showcasing my prowess in autonomous vehicles (Simulator) 2021.
- First Place in self-driving cars U19 competition of the IRAN Fira Cup's League (All-rounds) 2023.
- First Place in self-driving cars U19 competition of the IRAN Fira Cup's League (Simulator) 2023.
- 🏆 First Place in self-driving cars U19 competition of the IRAN <u>Fira</u> Cup's League (Race Simulator) 2023.
- First Place in the national robotics competition ROBOIUT, outshining competitors in solving maze-line challenges at the Isfahan University of Technology 2021.
- Second Place in self-driving cars Open competition of the IRAN Fira Cup's League (Race Simulator) 2023.
- Second Place in the open league of the Fira Cup's self-driving cars competition (simulator)2021.
- 🥉 Third Place in self-driving cars (Pro League) competition of the IRAN Tech Olympics (simulation league) 2024.
- 👗 Third Place in self-driving cars (Pro League) competition of the IRAN Tech Olympics (physical league) 2024 (Coach).
- Third Place in self-driving cars Open competition of the IRAN Fira Cup's League (All-rounds) 2023.
- 🥉 Third Place in self-driving cars U19 competition of the IRAN <u>Fira</u> Cup's League (Urban Simulator) 2023.

Education

- Currently studying BS in Software Engineering at Azad University, Iran (Present).
- Diploma Degree in Network and Software at Amirkabir Vocational School Academy of Brilliant Talents, Iran.
- Proudly possess the ICDL IRAN Association Certificate in Python, a testament to my expertise in the programming realm.

Languages

- English (C1) IELTS 7
- Persian (Native)